

Melbourne, VIC

Summary

Hey I'm Kat, a Junior Software Engineer with a flair for Front-End Development. I have experience across JavaScript, React.js & CSS / HTML and have a passion for crafting delightful user experiences.

Prior to transitioning into software development I've had over 7 years experience in the tech industry, with the past 4 working as a Product Manager in B2B SaaS companies.

I've always been an avid problem solver, and as a Product Manager I was tackling challenging problems alongside engineers. With my career transition I'm excited to start tackling user problems as an engineer myself.

I highly value teamwork and collaboration and am looking to join a team with aligned values that can support my growth as an engineer; whilst solving some wicked challenges along the way.

Kat Mountford

Junior Software Engineer

katricemountford@gmail.com 0402 449 403

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

Experience

CODER ACADEMY | SEP 2023 - MAR 2024

Software Engineering Student

After hands-on experience building a product in low-code through my experience as co-founder in Talk to Maple, I fell in love with coding and decided to pivot my career to pursue software engineering.

I completed a rigorous 6 month full time coding bootcamp with Coder Academy, receiving a Diploma of Information Technology. Gained hands on experience with a range of technologies including React.js, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Python and Flask; achieving HD results and completing 4 major projects.

TALK TO MAPLE | JAN 2023 - JUN 2023

Co-Founder | CPTO

Talk to Maple was a gamified, A.I. powered digital companion app, targeting young people (Gen-Z) to help them build better self-care habits and ultimately improve their mental health.

Starting as a passion project, my co-founders and I were accepted into Antler's startup accelerator program where we built and launched our gamified mobile application using low code tools. The App was launched across both iOS & Android App stores, gaining over 200 users and garnering very positive feedback.

Alongside leading the UX research and design, my responsibilities encompassed all Front-End development throughout the course of the project. This included successfully integrating with OpenAl Api's, conditionally rendering elements based on state, implementing Firebase Authentication and single-handedly building all UI components throughout the app.

CULTURE AMP | JUL 2022 - JAN 2023

Product Manager

Culture Amp is an Australian tech unicorn and the market leading employee experience platform. I was part of the core team developing their performance management product where my role focussed on reducing churn and increasing product usage. (continued below)

Skills

I have strong skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Express.js and MongoDB (MERN stack).

I've also had experience with Python, Flask, PostgreSQL and SQL.

Education

2024

Diploma of Information TechnologyCoder Academy

2021

UX / UI Design Bootcamp Academy XI

2019

Certified Scrum Master Scrum Alliance I uncovered key insights into feature utilisation and revenue churn risk metrics through targeted customer interviews and collaboration with cross functional teams. This resulted in a quarterly roadmap being produced to focus solely on churn reduction after successfully gaining strong stakeholder buy-in.

SURREAL | AUG 2021 - JUL 2022

Product Manager

Surreal (formerly known as Muso) is a Melbourne-based startup providing a SaaS platform for hospitality venues to manage their live entertainment.

As Surreal's first product manager, I led the product launch of their first international product into UK venues. This involved extensive market research which enabled me to ideate, wireframe and prioritise the product roadmap effectively resulting in over 60% of early adopters being retained after 2 months.

I simultaneously lead technical projects including implementing a full analytics stack featuring Amplitude, Fullstory, Google Analytics, and Metabase to support UX activities.

HENRY SCHEIN ONE | JAN 2017 - JUL 2021

Product Manager

Henry Schein One is the world's leading dental practice management software provider. As a Product Manager at Henry Schein One I worked on the core product team building their flagship cloud-based dental products, Ascend and Dentally.

As Product Manager of Ascend, I uplifted NPS by 30 points and doubled user growth over a 12 month period through understanding qualitative and quantitative inputs alongside business needs to curate and execute on a high impact product roadmap.

Dentally was an acquired UK product and as Product Manager I led the launch into the Australian market, through creating the internationalisation roadmap and leading development operations, resulting in a successful pilot launch and Dentally now being the preferred cloud dental platform in Australia

Senior Technical Support

As a technical support agent I handled all 2nd and 3rd level technical escalations. This included completing server migrations, managing system outages and writing, testing and running custom SQL scripts while providing excellent customer service and maintaining a 99.9% customer satisfaction score.